(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T16:47:54.360616",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
「だからあたしは世界を旅している。『オンガク』を見つけるために」
"That's why I'm traveling the world... to find 'music'."
「そう、この世界線ではそうなのね」
"Right, that's how it is in this worldline."
「だってうちは……キミのことが大好きだからさ！」
"Because I... just love you so much!"
「わためは『非常食』じゃないよ～！」
"Watame isn't 'emergency food'~!"
「きみを見たとき、ビビビってきたの！！」
"When I saw you, I felt a spark!!"
「そういう時はね、ば～っと麦ジュースを飲むに限るかな～？」
"At times like that, you just gotta chug some wheat juice, huh~?"
「ねえ、気になるなら今からここで私といっしょにやってみる？ 『ライブ』ってやつをさ」
"Hey, if you're curious, why don't you do it with me right here? Something like a 'live show'."
「ずっと来るのを待ってたよ。この世界に……『オンガク』を取り戻すことができるキミを」
"I've been waiting for you to come. The one who can bring 'music'... back to this world."
(世界がこんな風になって、どれくらい経っただろう)
How long has it been since the world became like this...
(どこまでも続く荒野、木々や植物に覆われ崩れた建物、砂漠に埋もれ傾く巨大なビル群)
Endless wilderness, ruined buildings covered in trees and vegetation, and massive skyscrapers buried in the desert and tilting.
(もうず～っと前に起きた災厄によって世界は滅びてしまった)
The world perished due to a calamity that happened long, long ago.
(そんな黄昏を迎えれた世界で……あたしは失われた文明の遺物を探すことを生業としている)
In a world that has met such twilight... I make a living searching for relics of lost civilization.
(浄水器や濾過器のような今でも使えるもの、使い道のわからない箱のようなもの、朽ちかけた布などなど……)
Things still usable like water purifiers and filters, box-like things of unknown use, decaying cloth, and so on...
(そういったものを手に入れて、旅人。として日々を過ごしながら、ずっと探しているものがある)
Acquiring such things and spending my days as a traveler... there is something I have always been searching for.
(それは遥か昔にこの世界から失われてしまった……『オンガク』というもの)
That is something called 'music'... which was lost from this world long ago.
(それが何かわからない)
I don't know what it is.
(どうして探そうとしているのかも……よくわからない)
Nor do I really understand why I'm trying to search for it...
(でも不思議とその声に、惹かれるのだ)
Yet, strangely enough, I am drawn to its resonance.
(……)
...
(だからあたしは世界を旅している)
That's why I'm traveling the world...
(答えを探して、さまよっている)
Wandering, searching for the answer.
(『オンガク』を見つけるために)
To find 'music'.
「さあ、今日もがんばっていくかー」
"Now then, let's do our best today too—"
幾千の儚い鼓動を
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats,
惜しみなく行き交う時を追い越して駆け抜ける世界…
passing without regret, running through a world outpacing time...
いくつもの名前といくつもの身体を
Juggling multiple names and multiple bodies,
使い分けてうまく生きているけれど
living skillfully though I am,
胸の奥痛いよ音立てて疼くよ
deep in my chest it hurts, throbbing with a sound.
きっと、心、生命、ここにあるから
Surely, because my heart and life are right here.
.exe あたらしい あした へ
.exe Toward a brand new tomorrow
.exe いま こぎ だす
.exe Setting sail right now
.exe 運命の波間にさらわれたくはない！！
.exe I won't be swept away in the waves of fate!!
幾千の儚い鼓動を
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats,
惜しみなく行き交う時を追い越して駆け抜ける世界…
passing without regret, running through a world outpacing time...
i pray among the stars わたしはいつも祈ってる
i pray among the stars, I'm always praying
熱い想いをぶつけたら奇跡さえ起こせるから！
If I pour my burning feelings, I can even cause a miracle!
この景色すべては淋しさで出来ている
All of this scenery is made of loneliness,
願うだけですぐにそばにいられた
just wishing was enough to be right by your side.
あの頃の姿を追い求めさまよう
Wandering, chasing after your appearance from back then,
きっと、火花、言葉、ここにあるから
surely, because sparks and words are right here.
.exe 懐かしい 歌声
.exe A nostalgic singing voice
.exe いま 聴こえる
.exe Can be heard right now
.exe 真空の中でも 受取れるのはなぜ
.exe Why can I receive it even in a vacuum
「通」じあうそのよろこびを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting with you,
場所も時間も飛び越えて 分け合える世代
a generation that shares beyond space and time.
「信」じあうことがすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that believing in each other is everything,
君をもう一度みつけたら 涙さえ輝くから
so if I find you once more, even my tears will shine.
.exe！
.exe!
幾千の儚い鼓動を
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats,
惜しみなく行き交う時を追い越して駆け抜ける世界…
passing without regret, running through a world outpacing time...
「通」じあうそのよろこびを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting with you,
場所も時間も飛び越えて 分け合える世代
a generation that shares beyond space and time.
「信」じあうことがすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that believing in each other is everything,
君をもう一度みつけたら 涙さえ輝くから
so if I find you once more, even my tears will shine.
(exe！exe！exe！)
(.exe! .exe! .exe!)
幾千の 儚い鼓動を
Thousands of fleeting heartbeats,
惜しみなく行き交う時を 追い越して 駆け抜ける世界…
passing without regret, running through a world outpacing time...
「通」じあうそのよろこびを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting with you,
場所も時間も飛び越えて 分け合える世代
a generation that shares beyond space and time.
「信」じあうことがすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that believing in each other is everything,
君をもう一度みつけたら 涙さえ輝くから
so if I find you once more, even my tears will shine.
.exe あたらしい あした へ
.exe Toward a brand new tomorrow
.exe いま こぎ だす
.exe Setting sail right now
.exe 運命の波間にさらわれたくはない！！
.exe I won't be swept away in the waves of fate!!
（もうこの世界には、人はあまり残っていない）
(There aren't many people left in this world anymore.)
（文明が崩壊して、インフラも何もかもなくなってしまったのだから、仕方ないことだと思う）
(Civilization collapsed, and infrastructure is completely gone, so I suppose it couldn't be helped.)
（だけど旅をしていると、何かに引き寄せられるようにだれかと出会うことがある）
(But when traveling, sometimes you happen to meet someone, as if drawn by something.)
旅をしていると、何かに引き寄せられるように誰かと出会うことがある。
When traveling, you sometimes happen to encounter someone, as if drawn by something.
こんな風に。
Like this.
こんにちは。
Hello.
こんにちは。あなたは？
Hello. And you?
私はAZKi。この世界の地図を作りながら色々なところを調査する、開拓者をしてるの。キミは？
I'm AZKi. I'm a pioneer exploring various places while making a map of this world. And you?
私は旅をしてるんだ。なくなってしまった大切なものを探すために。
I'm on a journey. To find something precious that I've lost.
大切なもの？
Something precious?
うん……音楽を。
Yeah... music.
そう。この世界線ではそうなのね。
I see. In this world line, it's like that.
でもあなたには覚えているはずだわ。
But I'm sure you remember it.
ん？
Hmm?
記憶にはなくても、胸の奥の深いところに、いっしょに過ごした時間……気持ちをひとつにした瞬間を。
Even if it's not in your memory, deep in your heart... the time we spent together... the moment our feelings became one.
だってあなたにとってそれは……とても大事なものだったはずだから。
Because to you, that must have been... something very important.
君好みアーカイブ 惨敗もマージン
Put your likes in an archive, I can't be bound by margins,
後悔しないの 君に近付いた
I don't regret getting close to you.
昨日の飾りを 引き千切って
Tearing apart yesterday's decorations,
さあ どうぞ お好きなの ear ear ear
Now go ahead and pick your favorite, ear, ear, ear.
煩い通りは 少し苦手なの
I'm not so fond of noisy streets,
繁華街の闇目を光らせる
Keeping a sharp eye on the dark alleys.
監視体制も ラクなもんじゃないね
The surveillance system isn't easy either,
迂闊に昼寝も 出来ないぐらいに
Hardly allowing me to take a careless nap.
小娘一人は 傘一本
A lone girl with just an umbrella,
爪を汚さずに 高みの見物
Watching from above without soiling her claws.
被った仮面は 私の真似？ 笑っちゃうね
Is that mask you're wearing imitating me? Makes me laugh.
恋の敵のシルエット
The silhouette of a rival in love,
重なる夜まで あと何時間
How many hours until our nights overlap?
泥棒猫はどっちなの？
Which of us is the home-wrecker?
ヘッドホンは 外さない方が いいんじゃないの？
Don't you think you should keep your headphones on?
君の攻略本 私のコレクション
Your strategy guide is my collection,
色形サイズ 全て取り揃えてます
All colors, shapes, and sizes gathered here.
二週間前は 可愛い赤色
Two weeks ago it was a cute red,
三日前は 確かりクールな青色
Three days ago it was a calm, cool blue.
今日の新作は 気強な紫
Today's new arrival is a bold purple,
明日は君のその隣の邪魔な娘
Tomorrow it's that bothersome girl right beside you.
恋の敵のシルエット
The silhouette of a rival in love,
重なる夜まで もうあと少し
Just a little more until our nights overlap,
黒猫が通り過ぎたら
If a black cat passes by,
十字路には気を付けて帰るのよ
Be careful at the crossroads on your way home.
君好みアーカイブ 惨敗もマージン
Put your likes in an archive, I can't be bound by margins,
後悔しないの 君に近付いた
I don't regret getting close to you.
昨日の飾りを 引き千切って
Tearing apart yesterday's decorations,
ああ これじゃだめなの？
Ah, is this not enough?
恋の敵のシルエット
The silhouette of a rival in love,
重なる一秒前瞬間に
Just a split second before we overlap,
警告はこれで最後よ
This is your final warning,
その可愛い耳をくれないかな？
Won't you give me those cute ears?
愛の残りのエッセンス
The remaining essence of love,
もう聞こえない 猫撫で声で笑う
I can't hear it anymore, laughing with a coaxing voice.
所詮人間はこの程度よ
Humans are nothing more than this after all,
百年も生きりゃわかることなの
You'll understand if you live for a hundred years.
有終のtea time
A triumphant tea time,
乾杯のvirgin
A toast to the virgin.
新しいページを今日も刻むの
Carving a new page today as well.
煩い獲物を 引き千切って
Tearing apart my noisy prey,
さあ どうぞ お好きなの
Now go ahead and pick your favorite.
変幻自在のネコミミアーカイブ
The ever-changing cat ears archive.
きっとわがままだけど
I'm sure I'm being selfish, but...
完全少女論 自分自身の気分上昇そうじゃん
Complete girl theory, lifting our own moods, right?
これって事前準備ってすごく重要でしょ
Isn't prior preparation super important for this?
ちょっと手を伸ばして
Reaching out your hand just a little,
きっと全然気付かない
And surely not noticing at all...
笑うよ 朝が来たら大丈夫
I'll smile, when morning comes it'll be alright.
だから感情論を君に投げつけて演じてる振りしてるけど
So I'm hurling emotional arguments at you, pretending to act...
完全妄想 いつも言いたいぐらい君は優しいけれど
Complete delusion, even though you're always kind enough to make me want to say it...
感情論を君に投げつけて演じてる振りしてるけど
Hurling emotional arguments at you, pretending to act...
完全妄想 いつも言いたいぐらい君は優しいけれど
Complete delusion, even though you're always kind enough to make me want to say it...
感情論を君に投げつけて演じてる振りしてるけど
Hurling emotional arguments at you, pretending to act...
完全妄想 いつも言いたいぐらい
Complete delusion, enough to always want to say it...
ちょっと手を伸ばして きっと全然気付かない
Reaching out your hand just a little, surely not noticing at all...
（……）
(......)
(...)
（さっきのは……なんだったんだろう）
(What on earth was that just now?)
（たくさんの人たちと、その人たちが発する熱気に包まれて、あたしはすごくワクワクしてた）
(Surrounded by so many people and the heat of their passion, I was so excited.)
（なんだかすごく懐かしい感じがした……）
(It felt somehow so nostalgic...)
ねえ、キミ、大丈夫？
Hey, are you okay?
え？
Huh?
なんか顔色が良くなかったからさ。
You didn't look too good.
あ、うちのはミオだよ。占い師をやってる。
Ah, I'm Mio. I'm a fortune teller.
ん、キミ、何かを探してるね？そう、占いに出てる。
You're looking for something, aren't you? It shows in my reading.
わかるの？
You can tell?
うん。よかったら話してみて。何か力になれるかもしれないし。
Yeah. If you'd like, talk to me. I might be able to help.
実は――
Actually...
なるほど。キミは「オンガク」を探してるんだね。
I see. You're looking for "music," aren't you?
それならあそこに行ってみればいいんじゃない？
In that case, why don't you try going there?
世界の果てにあるっていう、光の塔。そこには天使が住んでて、やって来た人の願いを叶えてくれるんだって。
To the Tower of Light, said to be at the edge of the world. An angel lives there, and they grant wishes.
だからそこに行ってお祈りをすれば、キミの探しものも見つかるんじゃないかな？
So if you go there and make a wish, you'll find what you're looking for.
親切にありがとう。そこに行ってみることにするよ。
Thanks for your kindness. I'll go check it out.
どういたしまして。でもお礼なんていらないって。
You're welcome. But I don't need any thanks.
ん？
Huh?
だってうちは……キミのことが大好きだから！ずっとずっと、前からね！
Because I... love you so much! From long, long ago!
遙か遠く続く果てなき道
Far away, continuing on an endless road,
それとしてもいつか辿り着くと信じて
believing we'll reach it someday.
たとえば今は辛くきびしくても
Even if it's painful and harsh right now,
小さな笑顔守る全部捧げて
sacrificing everything to protect that small smile.
心重なる言葉より強い絆に染め上げていく一つになることで
Dyed into a bond stronger than words with overlapping hearts, by becoming one.
記憶を辿る追憶の旅続けて あらゆる事を受け入れるから
Continuing the journey of reminiscence tracing memories, accepting everything.
言葉はいらないの それは永遠に
Words are unnecessary; that is forever.
いつも近くそばで居たけれど 気付かなくても今は遠く感じる
Always close by my side, though I didn't realize it, now it feels far away.
後を追いかけ絆から愛に変われば
Chasing behind, if the bond turns into love,
思いを込めた言葉の強さ信じている
Believing in the strength of words filled with feelings,
口にしたとき覚悟していた
I was prepared when I spoke.
未来を紡ぐために
To weave the future.
気が付けばほら心に宿る灯火 小さな光寄り添い合えば そう未来を指して
Before you know it, a light dwells in the heart; if small lights snuggle close, pointing to the future.
青く広がる晴れ渡る空見上げる
Looking up at the clear, expansive blue sky,
もう言葉すら要らないから ただ抱きしめていて
we don't even need words anymore, just hold me tight.
時は永遠に
Time is eternal.
いつも近くそばで居たけれど 気付かなくても今は遠く感じる
Always close by my side, though I didn't realize it, now it feels far away.
後を追いかけ絆から愛に変われば
Chasing behind, if the bond turns into love,
染め上げていく二人だけの秘密
a secret just for the two of us, dyed deep.
思いを込めた言葉の強さ信じて
Believing in the strength of words filled with feelings.
滅びていく このステラ
This dying stella,
絆を辿る ストーリー
a story tracing our bonds.
受け継ぐ想いが 生まれ変われますように
May the inherited feelings be reborn.
気づけばほら 心に宿る
If you notice, look, dwelling in the heart,
ともしび
a companion's small light,
小さな光 寄り添い合えば
if small lights nestle close together,
そう 未来を指して
yes, pointing toward the future,
青く広がる あれは晴る空
spreading in blue, that is the clear sky.
降り注げる
pouring down,
もう言葉すら 要らないから ただ抱きしめていて
even words are unnecessary, just hold me tight.
時は永遠に
Time goes on eternally...
降り注ぐ雨のような歓声
(Like a downpour of rain, cheers)
その中で、きらびやかな服を着たあたしは、幸せそうな笑顔で手を振っている。
In the midst of it, I, in glittering clothes, wave with a happy smile.
まるで もう一人のあたしのように！
As if I were another me!
世界の果てにあるという光の塔、
A tower of light said to be at the world's end,
「オンガク」を探すために、あたしはそこを目指すことに決めた。
to search for 'Music', I decided to head there.
何日かかるか分からないけど、幸いなことに時間はたくさんある。
I don't know how many days it will take, but luckily, I have plenty of time.
ただ……
Only...
お腹、空いた……
I'm hungry...
角巻わため: なんでわためを見てお腹を鳴らしてるの！？
Watame: Why are you looking at Watame and making your stomach rumble!?
獅白ぼたん: え、わかんないけど、なんかキミを見たら急に。
Botan: Uh, I don't know, but seeing you suddenly...
角巻わため: わためは非常食じゃないよ！見逃してくれたら、かわりにわためが歌うから～！
Watame: Watame isn't emergency food! If you let me go, Watame will sing for you instead~!
獅白ぼたん: ……歌？
Botan: ...A song?
獅白ぼたん: 歌って……なに？
Botan: Singing... what is that?
角巻わため: え、キミ歌を知らないの？
Watame: Eh, you don't know songs?
角巻わため: よ～し、じゃあわためが教えてあげるよ！歌っていうのはね……
Watame: Alrigh~t, then Watame will teach you! Singing is...
滅びていくこのステラ 絆を辿るストーリー
This dying stella, a story tracing our bonds.
受け継ぐ思いが 生まれ変われますように
May the inherited feelings be reborn.
目の前現れた 無表情は
The expressionless face that appeared before me
誰にも懐を見せないまま
leaving its breast shown to no one
事象が世界を歪ませて 光がただ眩しすぎたの
Phenomena distorted the world, and the light was simply too dazzling.
絢爛と照りつける 荒野に残した足跡
Footprints left behind in the brilliantly blazing wilderness
与えられたのなら 守るものだけ
If given, only what needs to be protected
滅びていくこのステラ 叶うことがないとしても
This dying stella, even if it cannot come true,
変えよう世界を 灯していく
let's change the world, lighting it up.
震える手がはじまった 意味を持たない銃口
A meaningless muzzle where trembling hands began
輝く星の下 わたしは今息をする
Beneath the shining stars, I am now breathing.
Break out
錆び付くストーリー すべてわかってしまおう
I'll figure out this rust-covered story completely.
名前を
Even if you were
呼んでくれていても
calling my name,
私に向けられていなかった
it wasn't directed at me.
消える日の前でただ
Standing still right before the day it fades,
立ち尽くして煙るハイ
smoke rises from the ashes.
命の理由が今答えを迫る
The reason for life now demands an answer.
伸びてゆくその中で息を殺した場所暗い
Growing within it, holding my breath in a dark place,
崩れた絆を振り払って
shaking off shattered bonds.
切り裂いて
Tearing through it,
お願いどうかそばにいて声が銃声に求めた
Please, stay by my side, my voice pleaded to the gunfire.
終わりと始まりの時間の中で
In the time between the end and the beginning...
瞳の奥に沈んだ
Sunk deep within my eyes,
食われかけている心に眠る
slumbering in a heart being devoured.
引き金にかけた指
A finger on the trigger
先が示す未来を祈るだろう
praying for the future it points to.
滅びてゆくこの捨てら、瞬きの数の傷
In this fading wasteland, scars numbering in blinks,
心がこのまま耐えてしまっても
even if my heart endures like this,
私の生まれた理由も手放さないでと願い
I pray not to let go of the reason I was born.
終わりと始まりの時間の中で
In the time between the end and the beginning...
私はかかげるよ
I will raise it high,
何度でも確かめられるよ、心の存在と名前を
to verify my existence and name time and time again.
あなたが生き抜いた世界はまだ私の中で息をする
The world you survived still breathes inside me.
光、光、光
Light, light, light
その星のようなきらめきが――頭に焼きついて離れない
That starlike sparkle is burned into my head and won't leave.
あの子がやっていたことはなんなんだろう…？
What on earth was that girl doing...?
「ウタ」だって言ってたけど…初めて聞く言葉だ
She said it was a 'uta', but... it's a new word to me.
だけど「ウタ」は、あたしの心の深いところに確かに染み込んできた……
And yet, 'uta' certainly soaked deep into my heart......
静かだな……
It's so quiet......
この世界は、ずっと静寂に包まれている
This world has always been wrapped in silence.
だけどさっきのあれは――「ウタ」は、そのどれとも違った
And yet, that from earlier—'uta' was different from any of them.
あれは、なんだろう……？
What on earth was that......?
あと別れ際にくれたこの頭につける道具は……？ 遺物……？
And the tool she gave me to put on my head at parting......? A relic......?
確か「ヘッドセット」って言ってた
She said it was called a 'headset'.
これを使えば……あたしもうたえるんだろうか
If I use this...... can I sing too, I wonder?
forever has gone,
today is infinity,
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory,
forever has gone,
today is infinity,
it's time to move on,
forever has gone,
two eyes in the face of billions of voices,
I saw the flashing lights move further in the distance,
dream was not meant to be,
and outside these walls that I have created,
the sound of stars colliding
echoes in the distance
and dreams they shatter
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
renew... the light... the dream...
the dream...
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams, today a faint memory
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on, it's time to move on,
forever has gone
and outside these walls that i have created
the sound of stars colliding
echoes in the distance
and dreams they shatter
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
renew... the light... the dream...
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams, today a faint memory
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on, it's time to move on,
forever has gone
「ウタ」を知ってから、数日が経った
Several days had passed since I learned about "Uta."
旅路は進み、ようやく光の塔がぼろげながらに見えてくる
The journey progressed, and at last, the tower of light came faintly into view.
(だけど)「オンガク」や「ウタ」について知っている人は、ほとんどいなかった
(However) almost no one knew anything about "music" or "songs."
(もしかしたらあたしは、ないものねだりをしているだけなのかもしれない)
(Perhaps I was just wishing for things that didn't exist.)
(でも……新しい出会いはあった)
(But... I had a new encounter.)
Ciaoooo! I'm Raora Panthera!
あたし、絵描きをやってるんだー！
I'm an artist!
きみを見たときビビッときたの！きみにはこれが似合いそう！
When I saw you, it clicked! This would suit you so well!
さらさらさらさら……っと、はい、プレゼント！
Slashes of brushstrokes... and there, a present!
プレゼント！
A present!
これ…あたし？
This... is me?
うん！ステージ衣装を着たキミの絵！So cute…！！
Yeah! A drawing of you in your stage outfit! So cute...!!
ちょ、ちょっとあたしにはかわいすぎない？
Th-Isn't this a little too cute for me?
そんなことないよ！すごくぴったり！
Not at all! It fits you so well!
そ、そうかな…？
I-Is that so...?
きみはこのステージ衣装を着て… Let's sing with me!!
You're gonna wear this stage outfit and... Let's sing with me!!
YEAH~
The knacks of surviving in this world
are being human and being right
Everyone keeps telling me to grow up fast
and it is so tough can't wrap my head around it
Your unfair rules
Ego trip into a loop,
We do belong nowhere in this world
Yet we are surviving, getting through anything,
Stay alive
Hated ones, naked hearts,
Worthless games that never end,
Found them in the darkness in the end
何が正しくて何が間違っているんだ
What is right and what is wrong,
僕はただ、
I am just...
ここで生きてると叫びたいだけ
I just want to scream that I'm alive right here.
I heard voices calling out my true name,
I will never give up or be swayed anymore
Nobody can stop me, this is the way I am,
I'll EXECUTE you, drop dead baby!!
YEAH~
Everyone wanna choose the right path only,
They would seek salvation in this closed world
Filthy hands and mind never get clean again though,
And it is so tough can't wrap my head around it
Cannot turn the clock back, cannot take a turn back,
We do belong nowhere in this world
Yet we are surviving, getting through anything,
Stay alive
Missing piece, warmth of hands,
Joys and even stabbing pains,
Found them in the darkness in the end
何が正しくて何が間違っているんだ
What is right and what is wrong,
僕はただ、
I am just...
誰だって、ここで生きてると叫んでいるのに
When everyone is screaming that they are alive right here...
Facing what they really want to do,
They'll make it at the cost of everything
Nobody can stop me, this is the way I am,
I'll EXECUTE you, drop dead baby!!
YEAH~
また失って、もう嫌になって、それでも消えなくて
Losing things again, getting so sick of it, and yet it still won't fade away...
その心の名を何と言うのだろう
I wonder what the name of that heart is.
僕はここで今、叫んでいるんだよ、君だって、
I am screaming right here, right now, and you too,
ここで同じように叫んでいるんだろう
are probably screaming in the same way right here.
I heard voices calling out my true name,
I will never give up or be swayed anymore
Nobody can stop me, this is the way I am,
I'll EXECUTE you, drop dead baby!!
YEAH~
So, this is the way I am
色とりどの かわいらしい衣装
Colorful and cute attire...
それは不思議とぴったりと体に馴染んでいた
It somehow fit my body perfectly.
衣装を身にまとい、ヘッドセットをつけて、歌うあたし
Clad in the outfit, wearing a headset, I sing.
あっちのあたしと、今のあたし。どっちが本物なんだろう?
The me over there, and the me now. Which one is the real me?
そういう時はね、難しいことは忘れてぱーっと楽しいことをするに限るかな。
At times like that, the best thing to do is forget difficult things and just have fun!
クレープを焼いたりとか、アロマで癒されたりとか、ベリーダンスを踊ったりとかして気持ちよくなれば、悩み事なんてどこかに飛んでいっちゃうものなんだよ。
Bake crepes, get healed by aroma, or belly dance to feel good, and your worries will just fly away somewhere.
そういうものなの?
Is that how it works?
うん、そういうものかな。
Yep, something like that.
だって世の中の大たいのことは、それがどう見えるかなんていうのは見る人次第なんだから。
Because most things in this world depend entirely on how the viewer sees them.
たとえばアキロゼのこの格好が、芸術的に見えるかセクシーに見えるかはあなたたち次第。みたいにね!ふふっ。
For example, whether Akirose's outfit looks artistic or sexy is up to you all. Just like that! Heh heh.
え、あー、うん。
Eh, ah, yeah.
そうだ、せっかくこうして出会えたんだから、いっしょに踊ろっか。あなたとアキロゼの二人で。
That's right, since we managed to meet like this, let's dance together. Just the two of us, you and Akirose.
え、でもあたし、踊ったことなんかないんだけど。
Eh, but I've never danced before...
大丈夫大丈夫!これはあなたのことだけに考えた踊り子アキロゼの振り付けだから。ね?ふふっ。
It's okay, it's okay! This is a dancer Akirose choreography designed just for you. Right? Heh heh.
とある竜の恋の歌
[Title: A Certain Dragon's Love Song]
音のない大地に
On a silent earth,
恋の歌 響けば
if a love song echoes,
黒いジャスハグルマ
a black gear...
止められる運命が弾けた
The fate that could have been stopped has burst open.
黄昏が
Twilight...
黄昏が還る
Twilight returns.
今 太古にしえより 世紀を爆破の
Now, from before antiquity, blasting the century...
恋 目覚めた
Love has awakened.
絆を求めて
Seeking bonds,
炎を吹き飛ばし
blowing away the flames,
破壊と再生
destruction and rebirth,
険しき君の重く
the heavy, steep burden of you...
重ねた絆の
Of our overlapping bonds,
行くえを両手で抱きしめた
I held their destination in both hands.
月が通る魂
The moon passes through the soul,
嘘もなく気高く
without a lie, noble and proud.
現実も抱えて
Embracing reality too,
呪くな恋もっと
an even more profound love,
愚かさ
foolishness...
月日やかり
Passing days and nights,
今 二人でラスズカの
now the two of us...
ときの重なり合った
overlapping times...
絆の行くえを
the destination of our bond...
両手で抱きしめた 終わりと始まり
holding in both hands, the end and the beginning.
ともがきみのきおく
Your memories together...
絆を 求めて
Seeking bonds,
この街は 走り出す
This town starts running.
儚いと 再生 ケダモノの銃幕
Ephemeral rebirth, the beast's curtain...
絆の 行方を
The whereabouts of bonds,
両手で 抱きしめた
Held tightly in both hands.
終わりと 始まり 遠き 君の 記憶
The end and the beginning, your distant memories.
どこか懐かしい誰かと出会う度に、頭に浮かぶ映像が鮮明になってくる
Every time I meet someone strangely familiar, the images in my head become clearer.
もう少しで……何かがわかりそうな気がした
I felt like I was just a little closer to understanding something.
それって、「ライブ」なんじゃないかな？
Could that be a live concert?
「ライブ」？
A live concert?
うん、そう。
Yeah, exactly.
私、旅芸人だから噂で聞いたことがあるんだけど、
As a traveling performer, I've heard rumors that
「オオンガク」があった頃にはよく開催されてたんだって
back when there was music, they used to hold them often.
ん……
Hmm...
そうだ。あたしは「ライブ」をやっていたんだ……
That's right. I was doing live concerts...
ねえ、気になるなら今からここで私といっしょにやってみる？
Hey, if you're curious, why don't we try doing it together right here?
え？
Eh?
ていうかやろうよ！あなたとならやってみたい！「──『ライブ』ってやつを！」
I mean, let's do it! I want to do it with you! That live concert thing!
とおくで きこえる
Heard far away,
わたしを よぶ こえ
a voice calling my name.
あなたの 涙の 理由を 知っててたはずなのに
Even though I should have known the reason for your tears,
乾く前に 枯れる前に 全て捧げようと あなたにだけ
before they dry, before they wither, I will give everything just to you...
なにを求めるのか 誰を愛すのかさえ わからず
Not knowing what I seek, or even who I love,
灰のように朽ちていく心に あなたのかけだけは
in a heart turning to ash, only your pieces...
手探りでも かたちをなぞれば 長い眠りのなか
even by groping in the dark, if I trace their shape, within the long sleep...
あなたを 夢見るでしょう ふたり乱れたあの日々を なんどでも 夜明けは あなたにだけ
I will dream of you, holding those chaotic days between us, dawn is for you alone...
空には もう果てがないから
because the sky has no end anymore.
なにを求めたのか 遠い日のわたしにいま 問いかけ
What did I seek? Questioning myself of those distant days...
砕かれ色褪せ落ちていく あのかけたちはどこへ
Shattered, fading, and falling, where have those pieces gone?
手探りでも
Even fumbling in the dark,
かたちをなぞった
I traced its shape.
長い夢の中で
Within a long dream,
いま
Now,
あなたと
with you,
また出会えた
we met once more.
ふたり願ったこの瞬間を
This moment we both wished for,
最後まで
until the very end—
広がる青い空が
spreads across the blue sky.
あなたをいつでも見ているから
I'll always be watching over you,
(光の塔はもう目の前に迫っていた)
(The tower of light was already right before my eyes.)
(それにつれて、頭に浮かぶ映像はさらに鮮明になってきていた)
(Along with it, the images in my head became even more vivid.)
(まるで夢から覚めるように、まるでそれが本物であるかのように、――「ライブ」をしていた場所が)
(As if waking from a dream, as if it were all real—the place where we held the "live"...)
……着いた。
...We've arrived.
ここが……光の塔。
So this is... the tower of light.
塔っていうよりも、何かの舞台みたいにも見えるな。
It looks less like a tower and more like some kind of stage, doesn't it?
似てる……気がする。あの、「ライブ」をやってた場所に。
It feels... a lot like that place where we held the "live."
いらっしゃい、ライオンさん。
Welcome, Lion-san.
キミが……願いを叶えてくれる、“天使”？
You're the "angel" who grants wishes...?
うん。さっ、キミが来るのを待ってたよ。
Yes. I've been waiting for you to come.
この世界に……「オンガク」を取り戻すことができるキミを。
You're the one who can bring "music" back to this world.
「オンガク」を、あたしが……？
Me...? Bring "music" back?
そうだよ。ここに来るまでにたくさんのものを受け取ってきたキミは、もう「オンガク」が何か分かってるんじゃないかな？
That's right. You've received so much on your journey here—surely you understand what "music" is by now, don't you?
ほら、ボクといっしょに飛ぼう。
Come on, let's fly together!
揺らめく世界の縁で
Fluttering down on the edge of the world,
私を抱きしめてください。
hold me tight in your arms.
静寂に埋め尽くされ
Buried and trapped in tranquility,
ひとりで凍えている。
even a single sigh echoes.
崩れ落ちてゆく楽園の果てで
The prayers left behind at the end of paradise
忘れられた祈りが響いてる支配する闇の中でも
glow even within the ruling darkness.
枯れない愛よ目覚めよ
Awakened love,
永遠に降る孤独を
sing out to the endless loneliness,
その指で染めてください。
and dye it with your fingers.
叫ぶこの心が
Scream from the bottom of your heart,
悲しみを愛せるように
just to taste the sorrow.
まだ見ぬあの光の景色へ
Fluttering down on the edge of the world,
揺らめく世界の縁で
hold me tight in your arms.
私を抱きしめてください。乱れ咲く花のより深く
Gently press your lips to the depths of this disarray,
優しくくちづけてください。儚い命と喫茶への命を
and guide my fragile breathing to the café.
灯火を灯して
Lighting the lamp,
滲む幻影 祝祭の風を
blurring illusions, the festival's wind,
その温もり二人伝うまで
until that warmth is shared between us two,
駆け抜ける 嵐の中も
running through even the storm.
音を走る 新しいの中も
Racing through sound, even inside the new,
やまない
unceasing—
愛を目覚めよ
awaken your love!
あなたへ想いを
My feelings toward you,
染めて 迎えてください
dye them and welcome me.
出会えた歓びに
In the joy of meeting you,
震えてる 裸の心で
trembling with a bare heart.
求める あの残酷の彼方へ
Seeking beyond that cruelty,
届け 交わそう 二人を
deliver and exchange the two of us.
踏み出せ 引き裂かれるルパリア
Step forward, into the tearing luparia—
光が届き 見えて ステージが上がるの 伸ばして
Light reaches, appearing as the stage rises, reach out!
こぼれ落ちる涙が
Tears falling down
キラキラと風に舞う頃
as they sparkle and dance in the wind.
絆の糸 瞳を潤して
Moistening your eyes with the thread of bonds,
永遠に消えないように
so that it never fades away eternally.
無限に降る 孤独を私に預けてください
Infinite falling, please entrust your solitude to me.
呼び合えた心が
Hearts that called out to each other
扉を放ち羽ばたく
open the doors and take flight.
近づく あの始まりの備えへ
Approaching that initial preparation,
光が届き 見えて ステージが上がるの 伸ばして
light reaches, appearing as the stage rises, reach out!
へぇ、この街の露店は品揃えがいいな。
Heh, the street stalls in this town have a really good selection.
他では見ない珍しいものがいっぱいでさ。
Full of unusual things you don't see anywhere else.
旅を続けてると、やっぱりどうしても装備品は必要になってくるからな……。
As you keep traveling, equipment inevitably becomes necessary...
ちょっと覗いていこう。
Let's take a peek.
あ、これいいな。「ブランケットインクッション」。
Ah, this is nice. A "Blanket in Cushion".
ブランケットなのに袋に収納すればクッションにもなるから、これがあればどこでも一休みできて旅のお供にぴったりかも。
It's a blanket, but when stored in its bag it becomes a cushion, making it a perfect travel companion.
コンパクトなのにふかふかで、寝心地もよさそう。収納袋の絵もいい感じ。
It's compact yet fluffy, and looks comfortable to sleep on. The drawing on the storage bag is also nice.
こっちはなんだろう？「SSRBミニウォレット」か。
What's this? An "SSRB Mini Wallet"?
買い物をしたり、小物を収納するのに財布は必需品なんだよね。小銭もお札も入れられるっていうのも嬉しいな。
A wallet is essential for shopping and storing small items. Being able to put both coins and bills in it is great.
今使ってるのも古くなってきたし、そろそろ買い替えてもいいかも。
The one I'm using now has gotten old, so maybe it's about time to replace it.
お、この「ブレスレット」、かっこいい。
Oh, this "bracelet" looks cool.
デザインが馴染みやすいから普段使いしやすそうだし、ライオンの加護もついてるんだ――。
The design is easy to get used to, and it even comes with a lion's protection—
これを付けてたらキミもライオンになれるかも？ なーんて。
If you wear this, maybe you can become a lion too? Just kidding.
ふふ、これかわいいな。ヘルメットかぶってる。
Hehe, this is cute. Wearing a helmet.
「SSRBぬいぐるみキーホルダー」。つけてるだけですっごく楽しい気分になれそう。
An "SSRB Plushie Keychain". Just wearing it will make you feel super happy.
手のひらサイズのちょうどいい大きさだからバックパックにぶら下げてもいいし、ベルトに付けるのとかもありかな。
It's just the right palm size so you can hang it on a backpack or attach it to a belt.
これも買いとこ、っと。
I'll buy this too.
どうしよう、全部欲しい……。どれにするか迷う。
What should I do, I want all of them... I can't decide which one to get.
え、これを全部まとめたセットもあるんだ？
Eh, is there a set that bundles all of these together?
しかもそれだと、収納袋の絵を描いてるトマリ先生の描き下ろしポストカードと直筆サイン、百推しメッセージ……が特典でついてくるのか。
And plus, it comes with a newly drawn postcard, an autograph, and a message as a bonus.
うーん……セットでください。
Hmm... I'll take the set.
……やっと分かった気がする。
I feel like I finally understand.
AZKi、みお、わため……
AZKi, Mio, Watame...
ラオラ、
Raora,
アキロゼ、
Akirose,
リオナ……
Riona...
かなた……
Kanata...
そしてこの舞台に向けて声援を送ってくれていたたくさんのみんな……
and all of you who sent your cheers toward this stage...
みんなから受け取ったたくさんのもの──
All the many things we received from everyone...
そこに込められた想い。
The feelings poured into them...
それらが集まって……「オンガク」になる。
When they all come together, it becomes "music."
新しいあたしが生まれるんだ。
A brand-new story is born.
うん、キミならそう言ってくれると思った。
Yeah, I figured you'd say that.
そんなキミにボクから……ボクたちから……最後に曲を送るよ。
So, from me to you, from all of us, we'll send you one final song!
今日という素敵な日の最後を飾る……新しい獅白ぼたんの誕生を祝う、世界で1つだけの曲。
To celebrate the very last moments of this wonderful day, and the birth of a brand-new Shishiro Botan—the one and only song in the world.
今のキミなら歌えるはず……「音楽」を取り戻せるはずだから。
You should be able to sing it now. You can take "music" back!
がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
がおっ！
Rawr!
15分早起きした
I woke up 15 minutes early today—
奇跡的な起床記録
a miraculous record for waking up!
珍しい誇らしい朝 誰のせいでしょうか？
Whose fault is this rare, proud morning?
きみのがおが聞こえると 気がするだけかもしれないけど
When I hear your "gao," it might just be my imagination,
無敵になる気がして 走って走って走れんだ
but it makes me feel invincible. Run, run, run!
(Shine on!) どこだって迷っちゃっても
Shine on! Even if I get lost, asking "Where?"
(Ride on!) 合図は遠くの声
Ride on! The signal is a voice from afar.
(Vibe on!) 迎えに行くよ We're Lions!!
Vibe on! I'm coming to get you. We're Lions!!
(Shine on!) きみがいる世界が 輝く合言葉
Shine on! The world you're in is a shining password.
がおっていいヤツ みんなで Everybody, say 1-2-3!!
Ga-otte-ii-yatsu! Everybody, say 1-2-3!!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
ひとりじゃないって魔法をかけたら
If I cast a spell that says "You're not alone,"
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
不安だって一緒に吠えて
we'll even roar at our anxieties together!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
笑顔でバフかけちゃえるから
Because we can buff each other with smiles!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
ここがそう 私達の最高 Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
Right here, this is our very best—Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
一日一獅子 Motivation 低めのやる気がおで上昇
One lion a day, motivation. My low motivation rises with a roar!
Join us my peeps! 百獣で優勝 だからがおっていきましょう
Join us my peeps! Let's win as the king of beasts, so let's all roar together!
靴ずれした右足が 今日のやる気を持っていった
My right foot with a blister took away my motivation for today.
椅子の角っこと小指も ついでにしばいてくれた
The corner of a chair also decided to strangle my pinky toe for good measure!
きみのがおが聞こえると そんな日もちょっとやさしくなり
When I hear your "gao," even days like that become a little kinder.
おすそ分けしたくて 踊って踊って踊ってんだ
I want to share it with everyone. Dance, dance, dance!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
ジャンプするなら今しかないし
If we're gonna jump, there's no time but now!
がおってこ がおってこ 高いトコ目指しちゃうおょ Let's go!
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko! Let's aim for a high place, let's go!
(Shine on!) “この一瞬がプレゼント”
Shine on! "This moment is a gift"—
(Ride on!) なんて真顔じゃ言えない
Ride on! I can't say that with a straight face.
(Vibe on!) だから吠えちゃうな We're Lions!!
Vibe on! So I'll just roar it out. We're Lions!!
(Shine on!) きみがいる毎日が 歌う合言葉
Shine on! Every day that you're in is a singing password.
がおっていいヤツ みんなで Everybody, say 1-2-3!!
Ga-otte-ii-yatsu! Everybody, say 1-2-3!!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
小声でもSayちゃんと聞こえてる
Even a whisper, say it, I can hear it clearly.
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
じゃあ叫んだら未来に届く!?
So if we shout, will it reach the future?
がおってこ がおってこ みんなでなら446dB
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko! Together we can reach 446 decibels!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
ここがそう 私達の最高 Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
Right here, this is our very best—Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
言葉にすると真っ直ぐすぎて くすぐったい胸の奥が
When I try to put it into words, it's too straightforward. It tickles deep in my chest!
がおってこ がおってこ
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko!
「ありがとう」のかわりを
Instead of saying "Thank you..."
がおってこ がおってこ ここがそう 私達の最高
Ga-otte-ko! Ga-otte-ko! Right here, this is our very best.
これは……あたしが見てる夢？
Is this a dream I'm seeing?
それとも「ライブ」をしてるあたしの方が、今のあたしが見てる……？
Or is it the me performing live that I'm seeing...?
ライブをしてるあたしの方が今のあたしが見てる夢……？
Live... Shishiro Botan: Or maybe the me doing a live show is the one the current me is dreaming of...?